Guide to the Corcoran Gallery of Art and Corcoran College of Art + Design, Corcoran Gallery of Art conservation department records, circa 1882-2019 COR0005.2.RG
Special Collections Research Center, The George Washington University
Corcoran Gallery of Art and Corcoran College of Art + Design, Corcoran Gallery of Art conservation department records
1882-2019
Special Collections Research Center, The George Washington University
COR0005.2.RG
16.75 Linear Feet
Conditions Governing Access
This collection is open to research.
When conducting research within The Corcoran Archives collections, please be advised of the following restrictions:
Records of the Board of Trustees (RG 1.0) and records of the Office of the Director (RG 2.0) are closed to research for 25 years from the date of creation.
Development records are closed to research (RG 3.2).
Access to student records is governed by the federal Family Educational Rights and Privacy Act (FERPA), which protects the privacy of student education records. Student records are closed for the lifetime of the student, and are presumed to be open 75 years after the date of record creation (RG 9.0 Series 4).
Personnel and financial records are closed for 50 years from date of record creation (RG 4.0).
Please see the Public Services and Instruction Librarian for assistance.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
The Corcoran Institution Board of Trustees donated these records to The George Washington University in 2016.
Arrangement
Organized into 6 series: Early Conservation records; Harold F. Cross records; Russell J. Quandt records; Robert Scott Wiles records; Dare Myers Hartwell records; and Conservation files transferred from the National Gallery of Art.
Historical narrative
The following history was prepared in 2019 by George Washington University SCRC staff with the support of the Luce Foundation.
According to accounts in the Corcoran Gallery of art Directors' records, paintings in the collection began to be sent out for repairs and touch-ups as early as 1886.
In 1946, the need for a regular program of care and conservation of the works of art in the collection was stressed during Board of Trustees proceedings, and in 1948 the Board of Trustees authorized the appointment of Harold F. Cross as the staff conservator, as well as the "necessary renovation and equipment" for a conservation laboratory. In 1951, Russell J. Quandt began his twenty-year affiliation with the Corcoran as its conservator. Robert Scott Wiles was the affiliated conservator from 1971-1983.
Prior to 1983, the Gallery's painting conservation was conducted by a private conservator using the Corcoran's facilities on a contractual basis. In order to better serve the needs of the collection, in 1983 the Corcoran established a conservation lab and hired full-time staff conservator Dare Hartwell. Dare Hartwell was responsible for the general care of the entire collection and treatment of paintings.
The conservation department's initial focus was on equipping the lab. Through matching grants from The National Endowment for the Arts from 1983-1986, the Gallery purchased over $45,000 worth of new conservation equipment. During this time, the Corcoran also completed a major climate control project that allowed for improvements in control of the environmental conditions within the building.
Between 1984 and 1987, Dare Hartwell conducted a general condition survey of all collections, storage and museum environments. While Hartwell treated paintings in the collection as time permitted in the course of her duties, the Corcoran obtained additional grants throughout the 1980s and 1990s to hire and contract outside professionals to survey and treat other types of objects in the collection. Specific grants from a variety of organizations including Getty Trust, Institute of Museum Services, and The National Endowment for the Arts allowed for the treatment of sculptures, works on paper, and textiles. Throughout all grant projects, the Corcoran Gallery curators worked closely with Hartwell and the contracted conservators.
In 1989, Dare Hartwell initiated a multi-step restoration project of the Salon Dore, the Corcoran's 18th-century French period room donated to the Corcoran in 1926 as part of the bequest of Montana Senator William A. Clark. The project included the removal of layers of dirt and overpainting from the walls and ceiling, restoration of damaged gold leaf by specialized craftspeople, and reproduction of the curtains weaved by French fabric house Tassinari & Chatel. The project completed with installation of the new curtains in 2001.
Scope and Contents
This record group contains records generated by the office of the Corcoran conservator over the lifetime of its operation, beginning with independent conservators contracted for work in the Corcoran Gallery building and collections. Material types include condition reports for works of art, conservation journals, correspondence, photographs, and charts documenting the environment in the galleries. Records date from 1882-2019.
Art; Artists; Museums; Washington (D.C.)
- Early Conservation records, 1932-1977; Series 1
  Scope and Contents
  This series contains two small notebooks containing early conservation records of L.J. Kohlmer, index cards created in 1977 containing an alphabetically-indexed transcription of the information contained in the L.J. Kohlmer notebooks, and correspondence of Associate Curator Eleanor Swenson related to conservation before the hiring of Corcoran's first contractor conservator Harold F. Cross. Records date from 1932-1977.
  - Pictures repaired by L.J. Kohlmer, Vol. I and Vol. II, 1932 July-1933 November; Series 1 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Old conservation report notes, index cards A-C, circa 1977; Series 1 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Old conservation report notes, index cards C-D, circa 1977; Series 1 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Old conservation report notes, index cards D-G, circa 1977; Series 1 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Old conservation report notes, index cards H-K, circa 1977; Series 1 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Old conservation report notes, index cards L-M, circa 1977; Series 1 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Old conservation report notes, index cards N-R, circa 1977; Series 1 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Old conservation report notes, index cards S-T, circa 1977; Series 1 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Old conservation report notes, index cards U-Z, circa 1977; Series 1 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Eleanor Swenson (Associate Curator), Conservation correspondence, 1947-1948; Series 1 (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Harold F. Cross records, 1948-1951; Series 2
  Arrangement
  This series is arranged chronologically.
  This series contains records created by Harold F. Cross, first conservator for the Corcoran who worked under contract from 1948-1951. Materials include a time log for conservation work, conservation notes, and agreements between Cross and private art owners for conservation treatment and photographing of their artworks. Records date from 1948-1951.
  - Conservation notes, circa 1949; Series 2 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Time Log, 1949-1950 April; Series 2 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Agreements with owners of works of art delivered to him, 1949 March-1950 March; Series 2 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Notes on the care of oil paintings in the home, Undated; Series 2 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Victor Amato (Photographer), Agreements with owners of works of art delivered to him, 1948-1951; Series 2 (Box 1, Folder 15)
- Russell J. Quandt records, 1950-1971; Series 3
  This series contains records created by conservator Russell J. Quandt in the course of his twenty-year affiliation with the Corcoran Gallery from 1951-1971. Materials include daily conservation notes, conservation reports, artwork condition forms, conservation billing records, agreements between Quandt and private art owners for conservation treatment, and photographs. Records date from 1950-1971.
  - Terms of Agreement between Russell J. Quandt and The Corcoran Gallery of Art, 1950-1960; Series 3 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Condition record forms, circa 1950-1970; Series 3 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Conservation billing, circa 1950-1970; Series 3 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Agreements with owners of works of art delivered to him, 1949-1951 February; Series 3 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Conservation Reports, 1950-1969; Series 3 (Box 1, Folders 20-21)
  - Conservation diary and planner, 1952; Series 3 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Conservation Memos, 1952-1969; Series 3 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Conservation correspondence, 1955-1963; Series 3 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Conservation photographs, Undated; Series 3 (Box 1, Folder 25)
- Robert Scott Wiles records, 1971-1983; Series 4
  This series is arranged in three subseries: Conservation reports and budget records; Correspondence; and Conservation of artworks records.
  This series contains records created by conservator Robert Scott Wiles in the course of his position as contract conservator from 1971 to approximately 1983. Materials include quarterly and annual reports prepared by Wiles for the Board of Trustees, budget records for conservation treatments, and files for individual works of art treated by Wiles during his tenure. Records date from 1971-1983.
  - Conservation reports and budget records, 1971-1979; Series 4 Subseries 1
    This subseries contains quarterly and annual reports prepared by Wiles for the Board of Trustees and budget records for conservation treatments. Records date from 1971-1979.
    - Annual and Quarterly reports, 1971-1979; Series 4 Subseries 1 (Box 1, Folder 26)
    - Conservation budget and billing, 1972-1973; Series 4 Subseries 1 (Box 1, Folders 27-28)
    - Conservation budget and billing, 1974; Series 4 Subseries 1 (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - Correspondence, circa 1971-1982; Series 4 Subseries 2
    This subseries contains a file of cards and postcards sent by artists to Robert Scott Wiles during his tenure as conservator at the Corcoran Gallery. Materials date from 1971-1982.
    - Cards from Artists, circa 1971-1982; Series 4 Subseries 2 (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - Conservation of artworks records, 1971-1983; Series 4 Subseries 3
    Records are arranged alphabetically by artist's last name.
    This series contains reports, mostly typewritten, describing condition of artwork reports and conservation treatment reports completed by Wiles. Some conservation files include photographs. Materials date from 1971-1983.
    - CGA paintings treated by Robert Scott Wiles, Undated; Series 4 Subseries 3 (Box 1, Folder 31)
    - Abbey, Edwin Austin - Sylvia, 1977; Series 4 Subseries 3 (Box 1, Folder 32)
    - Albers, Joseph - Homage to the Square "Yes", 1973; Series 4 Subseries 3 (Box 1, Folder 33)
    - Allston, Washington - Sketch for a Polish Jew, 1972; Series 4 Subseries 3 (Box 1, Folder 34)
    - Andre, Albert - La Fenetre Ouverte, 1979; Series 4 Subseries 3 (Box 1, Folder 35)
    - Andrews, E.F. - Portrait of President William Henry Harrison, 1972; Series 4 Subseries 3 (Box 1, Folder 36)
    - Andrews, E.F. - Portrait of President Rutherford B. Hayes, 1972; Series 4 Subseries 3 (Box 1, Folder 37)
    - Andrews, E.F. - Portrait of President Andrew Johnson, 1972; Series 4 Subseries 3 (Box 1, Folder 38)
    - Anshutz, Thomas Pollock - View of the Ohio, 1972; Series 4 Subseries 3 (Box 1, Folder 39)
    - The Antwerp painter - A Lady of the Pape Family, 1978; Series 4 Subseries 3 (Box 1, Folder 40)
    - Badger, Joseph - Portrait of Miss Grace Spear, 1983; Series 4 Subseries 3 (Box 1, Folder 41)
    - Barnet, Will - Multiple Images I, 1980; Series 4 Subseries 3 (Box 1, Folder 42)
    - Beaux, Cecilia - Sita and Sarita, 1981; Series 4 Subseries 3 (Box 1, Folder 43)
    - Bellows, George - Forty-Two Kids, 1981; Series 4 Subseries 3 (Box 1, Folder 44)
    - Benton, T. Hart - Landscape, 1980; Series 4 Subseries 3 (Box 1, Folder 45)
    - Bessau, Oscar - Great Falls, 1971; Series 4 Subseries 3 (Box 1, Folder 46)
    - Bierstadt, Albert - Buffalo Trail: The Impending Storm, 1971; Series 4 Subseries 3 (Box 1, Folder 47)
    - Bierstadt, Albert - The Last of the Buffalo, circa 1975; Series 4 Subseries 3 (Box 1, Folder 48)
    - Bierstadt, Albert - Mount Corcoran, 1973; Series 4 Subseries 3 (Box 1, Folder 49)
    - Bierstadt, Albert - Mountainous Landscape by Moonlight, 1974; Series 4 Subseries 3 (Box 1, Folder 50)
    - Bingham, George Baleb - Cottage Scenery, 1982; Series 4 Subseries 3 (Box 1, Folder 51)
    - Birch, Thomas - View of the Delaware near Philadelphia, 1980; Series 4 Subseries 3 (Box 1, Folder 52)
    - Blakelock, Ralph Albert - Indian Encampment, 1975; Series 4 Subseries 3 (Box 1, Folder 53)
    - Boldini, G. - After the Bath, 1972; Series 4 Subseries 3 (Box 1, Folder 54)
    - Bonheur, Rosa - Bull, circa 1977; Series 4 Subseries 3 (Box 1, Folder 55)
    - Bonnani, Pietro - Portrait of Jane Cocking Glover, 1977; Series 4 Subseries 3 (Box 1, Folder 56)
    - Bonnat, Leon - The Honorable Henry White, 1974; Series 4 Subseries 3 (Box 1, Folder 57)
    - Borie, Aldolphe - Camelias, 1978; Series 4 Subseries 3 (Box 1, Folder 58)
    - Boudin, Eugene - Fair in Brittany, circa 1975; Series 4 Subseries 3 (Box 1, Folder 59)
    - Boudin, Eugene - La Havre, circa 1975; Series 4 Subseries 3 (Box 1, Folder 60)
    - Breton, Jules - The Harvest, 1982; Series 4 Subseries 3 (Box 1, Folder 61)
    - Brooke, Richard N. - A Pastoral Visit, VA., 1973; Series 4 Subseries 3 (Box 1, Folder 62)
    - Brown, John George - Longshoreman's Noon, 1981; Series 4 Subseries 3 (Box 1, Folder 63)
    - Brown, William Mason - Still Life on a Marble-topped Table, 1981; Series 4 Subseries 3 (Box 1, Folder 64)
    - Bruce, Patrick H. - Peinture/Nature Morte, 1980; Series 4 Subseries 3 (Box 1, Folder 65)
    - Bruce, Edward - St. Pere, 1975; Series 4 Subseries 3 (Box 1, Folder 66)
    - Carles, Arthur B. - Untitled, circa 1975; Series 4 Subseries 3 (Box 1, Folder 67)
    - Carlson, Dines - The Brass Kettle, 1974; Series 4 Subseries 3 (Box 1, Folder 68)
    - Carlson, John F. - Woods in Winter, 1971; Series 4 Subseries 3 (Box 1, Folder 69)
    - Carriere, Eugene - Baby, 1977; Series 4 Subseries 3 (Box 1, Folder 70)
    - Cazin, Jean Charles - Angelus, 1977; Series 4 Subseries 3 (Box 1, Folder 71)
    - Cazin, Jean Charles - Ecouen on the Cliff, 1975; Series 4 Subseries 3 (Box 1, Folder 72)
    - Cazin, Jean Charles - The Great Windmill and Rainbow, 1978; Series 4 Subseries 3 (Box 1, Folder 73)
    - Cazin, Jean Charles - Homestead by the Sea, 1977; Series 4 Subseries 3 (Box 1, Folder 74)
    - Cazin, Jean Charles - The Lighted Cottage, 1978; Series 4 Subseries 3 (Box 1, Folder 75)
    - Cazin, Jean Charles - The Old Fortress, 1977; Series 4 Subseries 3 (Box 1, Folder 76)
    - Cazin, Jean Charles - Weary Wayfarers, 1978; Series 4 Subseries 3 (Box 1, Folder 77)
    - Chase, William Merritt - The Honorable William A. Clark, 1973; Series 4 Subseries 3 (Box 1, Folder 78)
    - Church, F.E. - Niagra Falls, 1973; Series 4 Subseries 3 (Box 1, Folder 79)
    - Cole, Thomas - The Departure, 1982; Series 4 Subseries 3 (Box 1, Folder 80)
    - Cole, Thomas - The Return, 1982; Series 4 Subseries 3 (Box 1, Folder 81)
    - Cole, Thomas - Return from the Tournament, 1979; Series 4 Subseries 3 (Box 1, Folder 82)
    - Cole, Thomas - Tornado, 1971; Series 4 Subseries 3 (Box 1, Folder 83)
    - Copley, Jonathan Singleton - Colonel Jacob Fowle, 1983; Series 4 Subseries 3 (Box 1, Folder 84)
    - Cornell - Box, 1971; Series 4 Subseries 3 (Box 1, Folder 85)
    - Corot, Jean-Baptiste-Camille - Dance of the Nymphs, 1974; Series 4 Subseries 3 (Box 1, Folder 86)
    - Corot, Jean-Baptiste-Camille - Gypsy with Mandolin, 1974; Series 4 Subseries 3 (Box 1, Folder 87)
    - Couder, E.G. - Flower Piece, 1978; Series 4 Subseries 3 (Box 1, Folder 88)
    - Courbet, Gustave - Landscape with Fisherman, 1974; Series 4 Subseries 3 (Box 1, Folder 89)
    - Courbet, Gustave - Ornans, 1974; Series 4 Subseries 3 (Box 1, Folder 90)
    - Courbet, Gustave - Paysage, 1974; Series 4 Subseries 3 (Box 1, Folder 91)
    - Cranch, Christopher Pearse - Castle Gandolfo, Lake Albano, 1975; Series 4 Subseries 3 (Box 1, Folder 92)
    - Cropsey, Jasper Francis - George Washington's Headquarters on the Hudson, 1974; Series 4 Subseries 3 (Box 1, Folder 93)
    - Cropsy, Jasper Francis - View of Mount Washington, 1979; Series 4 Subseries 3 (Box 1, Folder 94)
    - Cyup, Albert - Landscape with Cattle, 1983; Series 4 Subseries 3 (Box 1, Folder 95)
    - Dagnan-Bouveret, After Church, circa 1975; Series 4 Subseries 3 (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - Daubigny, Charles Francois, The Creek, 1979; Series 4 Subseries 3 (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - Daubigny, Sunset on the River, 1974; Series 4 Subseries 3 (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - Daubigny, Washerwomen, 1980; Series 4 Subseries 3 (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - Daugibny, The Willows, 1972; Series 4 Subseries 3 (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - Daumier, Honore-Victorin - Les Curieux a L'etalgne d'Estampes, 1972; Series 4 Subseries 3 (Box 2, Folder 6)
    - Daumier, Honore-Victorin - L'hotel Drouot, 1972; Series 4 Subseries 3 (Box 2, Folder 7)
    - Davies, Arthur B. - Stars and Dews' and Dreams of Night, 1971; Series 4 Subseries 3 (Box 2, Folder 8)
    - Davies, Arthur B. - The Umbrian Mountains, 1973; Series 4 Subseries 3 (Box 2, Folder 9)
    - Dawon, Manierre - Play, circa 1975; Series 4 Subseries 3 (Box 2, Folder 10)
    - de Camp - Woman Sewing, 1973; Series 4 Subseries 3 (Box 2, Folder 11)
    - Delacroix, Euguene - Tiger and Serpent, 1977; Series 4 Subseries 3 (Box 2, Folder 12)
    - Dewing, T.W. - Lady with a Mask, 1974; Series 4 Subseries 3 (Box 2, Folder 13)
    - Dickinson, Sidney - Portrait of the Artist, 1973; Series 4 Subseries 3 (Box 2, Folder 14)
    - Dove, Arthur Garfield - U.S.A., 1982; Series 4 Subseries 3 (Box 2, Folder 15)
    - Duncanson, Robert S. - Fruit Still Life, 1982; Series 4 Subseries 3 (Box 2, Folder 16)
    - Dunlap, William - A Family Group, 1974; Series 4 Subseries 3 (Box 2, Folder 17)
    - Durand, Asher Brown - Edge of the Forest, 1980; Series 4 Subseries 3 (Box 2, Folder 18)
    - Eilshemius, Louis M. - Down over the Pacific, Del Mar, California, 1975; Series 4 Subseries 3 (Box 2, Folder 19)
    - Elliot, Charles Loring - James C. McGuire, 1973; Series 4 Subseries 3 (Box 2, Folder 20)
    - Elliot, Charles Loring - Thomas Loraine McKenny, 1974; Series 4 Subseries 3 (Box 2, Folder 21)
    - Faed, John - Shakespeare and his Contemporaries, circa 1975; Series 4 Subseries 3 (Box 2, Folder 22)
    - Fantin La Tour, Henri - Arcadia Baigneuses, 1976; Series 4 Subseries 3 (Box 2, Folder 23)
    - Fantin La Tour, Henri - La Toilette, 1978; Series 4 Subseries 3 (Box 2, Folder 24)
    - Fisher, Alvin - Autumnal Landscape with Indians, 1983; Series 4 Subseries 3 (Box 2, Folder 25)
    - Fisher, Alvin - Mishap at the Ford, 1981; Series 4 Subseries 3 (Box 2, Folder 26)
    - Fisher, Alvin - Mishap at the Ford, 1818, 1972; Series 4 Subseries 3 (Box 2, Folder 27)
    - Forain - Court Scene Interior, 1977; Series 4 Subseries 3 (Box 2, Folder 28)
    - Fortuny Y Carbo, Mariano - The Choice of a Model, 1978; Series 4 Subseries 3 (Box 2, Folder 29)
    - Francis, John F. - Still Life with Silver Cake Basket, 1982; Series 4 Subseries 3 (Box 2, Folder 30)
    - Frere, Pierre - Preparing for Church, 1981; Series 4 Subseries 3 (Box 2, Folder 31)
    - Fries, Charles - Too Late, 1971; Series 4 Subseries 3 (Box 2, Folder 32)
    - Frieske, Frederick - Peace, 1982; Series 4 Subseries 3 (Box 2, Folder 33)
    - Frothingham, James - John Pedrick III, circa 1975; Series 4 Subseries 3 (Box 2, Folder 34)
    - Frymire, Jacob - Portrain of a Man, 1979; Series 4 Subseries 3 (Box 2, Folder 35)
    - Fuller, George - Evening Lorette, 1977; Series 4 Subseries 3 (Box 2, Folder 36)
    - Fuller, George - Portrait of a Young Girl, 1982; Series 4 Subseries 3 (Box 2, Folder 37)
    - Gainsborough, Thomas - Portrait of John Gainsborough, 1980; Series 4 Subseries 3 (Box 2, Folder 38)
    - Garber, Daniel - South Room Green Street, 1975; Series 4 Subseries 3 (Box 2, Folder 39)
    - Gay, Timothy - Ralph Earl, 1972; Series 4 Subseries 3 (Box 2, Folder 40)
    - Gervex - Group at Table, 1972; Series 4 Subseries 3 (Box 2, Folder 41)
    - Gifford, Robert S. - October on the Coast of Massachusetts, 1974; Series 4 Subseries 3 (Box 2, Folder 42)
    - Glackens, William - In the Luxembourg Gardens, 1977; Series 4 Subseries 3 (Box 2, Folder 43)
    - Graham - Lady with Cat, 1982; Series 4 Subseries 3 (Box 2, Folder 44)
    - Guardi, F. - Santa Maria Della Saluti, 1979; Series 4 Subseries 3 (Box 2, Folder 45)
    - Guillaume, Louis M.D. - Commodore Matthew Fontaine Maury, 1971; Series 4 Subseries 3 (Box 2, Folder 46)
    - Gullager, Christian - Samuel Barton, 1976; Series 4 Subseries 3 (Box 2, Folder 47)
    - Gutherz, Carl - Susan B. Anthony, 1980; Series 4 Subseries 3 (Box 2, Folder 48)
    - Harding, Chester - John Randolph of Roanoke, 1976; Series 4 Subseries 3 (Box 2, Folder 49)
    - Hayes, W.J. - Hanging Game Birds, 1975; Series 4 Subseries 3 (Box 2, Folder 50)
    - Healy, G.P.A. - The Honorable J.S. Morrill, 1976; Series 4 Subseries 3 (Box 2, Folder 51)
    - Healy, G.P.A. - Portrait of Abraham Lincoln, 1975; Series 4 Subseries 3 (Box 2, Folder 52)
    - Healy, G.P.A. - Portrait of George Peabody, 1976; Series 4 Subseries 3 (Box 2, Folder 53)
    - Healy, G.P.A. - Portrait of President John Tyler, 1972; Series 4 Subseries 3 (Box 2, Folder 54)
    - Healy, G.P.A. - Presidential Portraits (various), 1972; Series 4 Subseries 3 (Box 2, Folder 55)
    - Heaton, A.G. - W.W. Corcoran, 1973; Series 4 Subseries 3 (Box 2, Folder 56)
    - Henner, Jean Jacques - Woman Standing, 1980; Series 4 Subseries 3 (Box 2, Folder 57)
    - Henri, Robert - Seated Nude, 1980; Series 4 Subseries 3 (Box 2, Folder 58)
    - Henry, E.L. - The Old Westover Mansion, 1973; Series 4 Subseries 3 (Box 2, Folder 59)
    - Hinckley, Thomas Hewes - Stag in the Adirondacks, 1973; Series 4 Subseries 3 (Box 2, Folder 60)
    - Hobbema, M. - Landscape with Figures, 1979; Series 4 Subseries 3 (Box 2, Folder 61)
    - Hobbema, M. - Landscape with Figures and Ruins, 1979; Series 4 Subseries 3 (Box 2, Folder 62)
    - Hoffman, Hans - The Golden Blaze, 1979; Series 4 Subseries 3 (Box 2, Folder 63)
    - Hopper, Edward - Ground Swell, 1980; Series 4 Subseries 3 (Box 2, Folder 64)
    - Hunt, William Morris - Niagra Falls, 1975; Series 4 Subseries 3 (Box 2, Folder 65)
    - Huntington, Daniel - Mercy's Dream, 1971; Series 4 Subseries 3 (Box 2, Folder 66)
    - Huntington, Daniel - Portrait of Joseph Henry, 1976; Series 4 Subseries 3 (Box 2, Folder 67)
    - Inness, George - Landscape, 1977; Series 4 Subseries 3 (Box 2, Folder 68)
    - Inness, George - Sunset in the Woods, 1973; Series 4 Subseries 3 (Box 2, Folder 69)
    - Inness, George - Tenafly, Autumn, 1976; Series 4 Subseries 3 (Box 2, Folder 70)
    - Isabey, Eugune Louis Gabriel - Country Tavern Feasting, 1977; Series 4 Subseries 3 (Box 2, Folder 71)
    - Isabey, Eugune Louis Gabriel - The Feast, 1973; Series 4 Subseries 3 (Box 2, Folder 72)
    - Isabey, Eugene Louis Gabriel - Wedding Festival, 1980; Series 4 Subseries 3 (Box 2, Folder 73)
    - Jennys, William - Woman with a Fan, 1972; Series 4 Subseries 3 (Box 2, Folder 74)
    - Johansen, John C. - Portrait of C. Powell Minnigerode, 1974; Series 4 Subseries 3 (Box 2, Folder 75)
    - Johnson, Eastman - The Earring, 1972; Series 4 Subseries 3 (Box 2, Folder 76)
    - Johnson, Eastman - Girl and Pets, 1974; Series 4 Subseries 3 (Box 2, Folder 77)
    - Johnson, Eastman - Portrait of a Child, 1974; Series 4 Subseries 3 (Box 2, Folder 78)
    - Jongkind, Johann Barthold - Le Bolder de Zouteveu Pres Delft, 1978; Series 4 Subseries 3 (Box 2, Folder 79)
    - Jongkind, Johann Barthold - Dutch Village, 1978; Series 4 Subseries 3 (Box 2, Folder 80)
    - Jongkind, Johann Barthold - Moonlight Coast Scene, 1978; Series 4 Subseries 3 (Box 2, Folder 81)